This one's really exciting. Let's talk about the three hook types. All right?
Hooks are less than 5% of most creative length, yet can impact the imp,
yet can impact their performance of an average ad creative by up to 25%.
Bad hooks almost always lead to poor performing ad creatives. Okay? This is so,
so, so, so, so, so, so important. Look, they're only 5% of the video,
but they can impact the video by 25%. That's huge. That's,
it's like the only thing that, like if your video sucks,
change the hook and it'll give you wildly different performances. Okay?
This is like, this is video ads number one. Um, and I,
it's still something that video creators don't understand yet.
And it's because the, uh, the performance marketing world has really made this,
um, very clear when it comes to testing ads versus, uh, organic,
organic place. In the organic world, it's harder to test because you,
you're only limited to a certain amount of people. But in the performance world,
you know, you can test 10 to 20 different hooks and you'll,
you'll get wildly different results. And, uh, out of those 2020 results,
like maybe one or two of those will land. And boom, now you've got,
you've got yourself a winning ad. When, if you didn't test those hooks,
you wouldn't have known, which actually worked,
and you probably would've given up sooner. So this is huge.
This is so huge. And as an editor,
I believe it's our job to be able to organize these hooks for clients in a,
in a clear way, and so that they have the assets ready. Um, and, you know,
you hand it off to them and they're just gonna deploy 'em and see how they do.
So the media buyers aren't gonna do this. Like,
it's our responsibility to generate these hook variations for them.
Okay? So hook number one, these are your emotional hooks. Uh,
these hooks make you feel something, make you feel, all right.
So these are your fear, your worry, fomo. If you don't know what FOMO means,
if you're, you're missing out humor, sadness, anger, and justice, excitement,
nostalgia, aspiration, or shock. All right, let's,
if we go back to the other example, um,
actually I'll break that down in a second. But in the three spirit example, um,
oops, sorry. Going back, going back
in the three spirit example, it makes you feel all right. The thing that, um,
I used in that was excitement. Okay? She was very excited.
She was shocked. All right? She was shocked by it. Whoa, what is this? Um,
and there's a little bit of humor in there.
So you can have more than one emotion happening.
'cause we're very complex people. We're, we're human beings,
you know what I mean? We're not one dimensional, we're not robots.
So there can be a lot of emotions happening at once here.
Number two are sensory hooks. These things make you look and listen,
and these are your visuals, your catchy music, any movement, color, contrast,
volume, loud noises or scenery or landscape, alright? Uh,
for that video example,
I used visuals as well as movement and color. Um,
there's even a little bit of catchy music in there happening.
So I use all those layers to create a very, uh,
sensory driven hook. And I think you should do the same thing every single time,
as much as you can. It's a practice, and it's a discipline.
But when you're able to understand the three different hooks and apply them each
time, your videos are gonna perform way better. Okay? Lastly,
you have your intellectual hooks makes you think, all right?
These are superlatives bold claims, drop in cliffhanger,
visual demonstration, social proof, sparks, curiosity,
strange off and odd things. Credibility, expertise,
and relatable things. All right?
So in that co in that video specifically, um,
I used a bold claim and I sparked curiosity, and it was kind of strange.
So what I wrote down was, um, you know, how to get,
how to get a buzz without the hangover. That's, that, that itself is a,
it's a very, like a curiosity provoking claim, and it's a bold claim.
So that itself is a hook.
But when you tie in hook number two and hook number one,
you've got this massive hook,
this massive attention grabber that's not one dimensional,
but it's multi-dimensional and that's why it's so effective. All right?
So moving on. The best hooks combine all three, I just mentioned that.
But the best hooks make you feel, they make you look and listen,
and they make you think if you can do all three and one single hook,
boom, you've got yourself a very scroll stopping ad, uh,
or video. So let's break this down.
As I mentioned the three spirit ad
in for the feeling hooks, we included humor, excitement,
and shock for the look and listen,
we used a visual appearance reaction and a bleep. And, um,
I'll play this for you actually real quick and let me put my speakers on so you
can hear it. Okay,
let me turn on and we'll just play the hook so you guys can see it.
Okay, so that's the first 10 seconds, right? Let's go back to that hook.
So this is the, uh, grabber, I'm sorry, the, the, the interest portion.
Okay? So layer number one, I added a voiceover that says how,
how to get a buzz without the hangover.
That's very common in social media these days. The second portion is,
I added the caption, the title right here,
how to get a Buzz Without the Hangover. That's layer number two.
Boom, I have her reaction. That's layer number three.
And then she says a cuss word with a graphic over it. That's layer number four.
I even added a nice little zoom in there.
Watch it one more time. Alright,
so if we go back to the training here,
you saw that there was humor in there, there was excitement, there was shock,
all right? Um, there was a visual aspect to it. There's a reaction,
there's a bleep. And then it also makes you think,
because there's a claim in there, there's a little bit of curiosity, right?
You don't, you don't know what this is,
but you're intrigued because you want those results.
You wanna buzz without the hangover. Everyone does, right?
So let's go over hook number two. And this video did very,
very well for us as well. So let's watch this.
All right, I had to go grab the add, but let's watch it right now.
All right?
All right. So first 10 seconds of the video, let's rewatch that hook.
Okay? That's a two second hook right there. And what we are seeing right now,
we've got headline caption, we've got a voiceover,
we've got some weird thing going on where it looks like she peed herself.
And you've also got an arrow coming in, right? The video itself is sped up,
so it's grabbing your attention. And so let's go back.
We can watch it one more time.
All right. So hook breakdown. We, um,
In this example, there's a shock factor. There's a fear factor.
No one wants to pee themselves or catch themselves leaking.
The product itself are leaked proof panties. So, you know,
this is like ev someone's worst nightmare.
And so we definitely don't wanna be showing that off, um,
or anybody wants to be experiencing that. Uh, uh,
when it comes to looking and listening,
there's obviously a visual demonstration. There's an arrow,
there's an audio hook. Uh, it's very, very visual here.
And then lastly, what it makes you think,
how to prevent bladder leaks in public.
So there is a correlation to the caption as,
as well as the, the visual hook. So those are two interconnected things.
So this is gonna attract someone's attention.
Who ex is experiencing this pain or this potential problem?
So every hook is designed to attract a different type of customer's pain.
Depending on the hook, it'll attract a completely different avatar. All right?
So we've tested different videos with, you know, um,
especially for the, the leakproof panties, you know,
tampons and pads and other things that are related to
same issue.
But people pinging themselves became the primary angle,
the primary hook that worked the best. Uh,
and it took us a while to get to that point, but once we found it,
then once we nailed it, we could scale it. So that took some work.
But I believe it's possible for any product.